Finding Aid for the Philippine Zines Collection LSC.2281
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Collector's Value, 2017; Yu, Ev (Box 2, Folder 27)
  A risograph printed zine that uses only primary colors.
  Risograph; Art
- Color Me Bad, 2017; Trinidad, Nick (Box 2, Folder 28)
  An adult-themed coloring book by Nick Trinidad. The works in this comic book feature women in the nude, or in suggestive outfits and poses.
  Coloring Book; Nudity; Art
- Coloring And Activity Zines, 2015-2017; Skye, Lukinda (Box 2, Folder 29)
  Coloring books by the same artist with different themes ranging from food and fashion, to crime scenes. Some of the coloring books are more interactive, prompting the user to also use their imagination and draw in some of the pages.
  Coloring Book; Fashion; Food; S.O.C.O.: Scene of Crime Operatives; Art
  - Favorite Exhibit Food, 2015 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Color Your Rage, 2015 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - SOCOlorful Adventures, 2015 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Art Scenery, 2015 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Colorful Words, 2016 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Dressing For The Vernisage, 2017 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Fashionablee, undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Congratulations, You're a Girl!, 2016 (Box 10, Folder 21)
- Copy Paste, undated; Tiu, Pau; Bad Student (Box 2, Folder 30)
  A 2-color risograph zine that contains a cut and paste collage in blue, black, and white.
- Corpus Delicti, undated; Strongwill, Porcupine (Box 2, Folder 31)
  A short story by a Messiahian artist from Manila about a super smart young girl, her aunt's failing marriage, and the chase to reveal her uncle's misdoings.
  Adultery; Relationship; Crime; Literature
- Cosmic Friends Osmosi, 2013 December; QBCCC (Box 2, Folder 32)
  This comic is collaborated by a group of friends and tells a story from the perspective of a cat.
  Barkada; Collaboration; Art
- Count The ****, undated; Soriano, Gerome (Box 2, Folder 33)
  A compilation of colorful photography from Pasig to Quiapo that captures sari sari stores, people, flyers, parol, jeepneys, and more.
  Photography; Pasig City (Manila, Philippines); Quiapo (Philippines); Stars; Art; Geography
- Cupcake and Muffin, undated; Aquino, Ardie M.; Abaya, Xana (Box 2, Folder 34)
  This is a collection of four panel comic strips in Taglish that shows the playful banter between "Cupcake" and "Muffin" as they go on their real life adventures.
- Daddy! Issue No. 1/Mommy! Issue No. 1, 2014 July; Gonzales, Paulyne; Cledera, Shaunnah Ysabel; Mendoza, Pamela; Magpies Press (Box 3, Folder 1)
  This is a two-sided zine published by Magpies Press in 2014. The zine is focused on abusive and traumatic relationships between the creators and their mothers/fathers. It contains poems, comic strips, and illustrations in English and Tagalog to portray the negative impact that parent's actions, expectations, and words have taken on their children's mental and emotional health.
  Intergenerational Trauma; Drug Abuse; Mental Illness; Sexual Abuse; Abuse; Death; Colonization; Culture; Health; Language; psychology; Religion
- Dayawen, 2016; Gallego, Mikael Rabara; Librong LIRA (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Ilokano poems based on the epic poem, "Biag ni Lam-ang."
  Ilocos (Philippines); Folklore; Language; Literature; Lam-ang, Biag ni
- Dear Diary, undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Dentista Ni Tomas, 2014; Casanova, Raphael Cezar; Rodriguez, Ruth Hanzessa F.; Office of the Public Health Dentist of the Rural Health Unit (Rosales, Pangasinan) (Box 3, Folder 3)
  Dentista Ni Tomas is a comic that was created in collaboration between the Office of the Public Health Dentist of the Rural Health Unit in Pangasinan and Ruth Hanzessa Rodriguez for the National Oral Health Month Celebration. The comic is aimed to teach children morals of good oral health, and was distributed to dental clinics and public schools in the Philippines.
  Health Service; Oral Health; Education; Health
- Derail, 2017; Batocabe, Emen (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Derail is a collection of sketches in black ink that is thematically centered around the war on drugs that president Rodrigo Duterte waging on poor people of the Philippines. Some of the images depict the infamous duct-taped heads used to hide the faces of the victims.
  War on Drugs; Violence; Drug War; Corruption; Art; Politics
- A Desperate Tenderness, 2016; Delgado, Dana Lee; Cubaohaus (Box 1, Folder 12)
  A chapbook with an assortment of short letters dedicated to different things. The short fragments are split into four parts: A memory, a dream, I, and to Dearest.
  Death; Mental Health; Literature
- Destroyer, 2016 December; Villanueva, Julius; Azhdarchid Komix (Box 3, Folder 5)
  A comic about a rebellious young girl who gets scolded for acting "like a tomboy" because she wears her hair short and loves to skate.
  Barkada; LGBT; Skateboarding; Culture
- Devour, undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Dill, volume 1, 2016 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Dirty Laundry and Other Stories, 2013; Rina, Danielle (Box 3, Folder 6)
  In this mini comic, Danielle Rina introduces herself a socially avoidant person who likes to drown in music, eat fast food late at night, and overthink past interactions with friends.
  Mental Health; Social Anxiety; Introvert; Art; psychology
- Displacement, undated (Box 10, Folder 26)
- Disminoriya: Modernong Maria Clara, undated; Kalye, Lapis Sa; 8Letters (Box 3, Folder 7)
  A collection of poems and short stories that talk about the different experiences and struggles of modern Filipina women and girls. It is in Taglish and some shorties include photos.
  LGBT; Feminism; Women; Menstruation; Maria Clara; Anthropology; Culture; Health; Religion; Literature
- Dok Malubha Unang Labas, 2016 (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Don't be a drag, just be a Queen, undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Don't Think About It: A Growing List of Things To Not Think About, 2013; Bacani, Mika (Box 3, Folder 8)
  This zine presents a list of things thought about as the creator went through a period of depression from 2013-2014. The illustrations and comic strips touch on comfort food, nostalgia, random musings about ukay ukay, and difficulty with social interactions.
  Depression; Ukay-Ukay; Mental Illness; Art
- Doom Mountain, undated; Africa, Dean Zuberi (Box 3, Folder 9)
  This item is the third installation to Dean Zuberi Africa's self published Doom Mountain comic series. The first few pages of the comic shows a chained up man being held captive on Doom Mountain before he was forced to take a concoction that gave him fearful visions and hallucinations. The panels of the comic are not accompanied with dialogue or words.
  Visions; Hallucinations; Spells; Art
- Dreams, 2017; Rival, Judy (Box 3, Folder 10)
  A zine with photos and text that reveals Judy Rival's childhood dreams.
  Childhood; Anime; Childhood Dreams; Culture
- Dulces Sueños, 2015 March; Collado, Daniel; Gazmen, Laraine (Box 3, Folder 11)
  Dulces Suenos was created in 2015 by Daniel Collado, a Spaniard artist in the Philippines. The comic follows Ana, a young woman who dreamt that her parents died, only for them to pass the following morning.
  Death; Therapy; Dreams; psychology
- Dust of Men, 2014 May; Zicarelli, Costantino; Nine Iron (Box 3, Folder 12)
  Dust of Men is a zine that contains grey graphite drawings of skulls, occult elements, and other distorted figures.
  Death; Graphite Drawings; Anthropology; Art; Culture; Philosophy
- Dwopke, 2014, 2017; Meatfist; Villa, Noel (Box 3, Folder 13)
  Dwopke is a collaborative zine between Meatfist and Noel Villa. The content of the zines are stream of thoughts jotted down and provided illustrations in hopes to unravel the secrets of the unconscious.
  psychology
  - Dwopke, 2014 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Dwopke, 2017 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Eating Behavior, 2017; Goy, Abi (Box 3, Folder 14)
  This zine illustrates some of Abi Goy's random memories of food from her childhood.
  Food; Nostalgia; Culture
- Eh Ano Ngayon, 2013; Nada, Marcushiro; National Gulaman Authority (Box 3, Folder 15)
  "Eh Ano Ngayon" translates to "So What Now." compilation of Marvel superheroes depicted in funny, compromising, or both situations.
  Superheroes; Caricatures; Culture; Film
- EM Zine, 2012, 2013 December; Ko, Trizha; Recto, Ronaldo; Puangco, Wina (Box 3, Folder 16)
  EM zine is a collection of prose, poems, and panel-style illustrations of fictional works across various topics, but mostly, relationships.
  Sexuality; Drag Queen; Art; Literature
  - EM 1, 2012 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - EM 3, 2013 December (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Empty Your Cages, 2014; Ligot, Kabel Mishka; Or, Mary Elizabeth (Box 3, Folder 17)
  Empty Your Cages is a zine that consists of five English poems by Kabel Mishka Ligot, and an illustration to match each one by Mary Elizabeth Or. The poems are about Jesus, swimming pools, and moaning. The subjects of these poems reflect the tensions that arise when queerness, sexuality, and religion are all put in the same arena.
  Poetry; Sexuality; Homosexuality.; Catholicism; Literature; Religion
- En Canto, undated (Box 10, Folder 36)
- Engaging Rivers and Mountains, 2013; Campos, Rolf (Box 3, Folder 18)
  Separated Materials
  This illustrated zine shows a storm over the Philipphines.
  Typhoons; Storms; Art; Culture; History
- Everyday Demons, 2016 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  A compilation of comic strips, illustrations, and poetry by different artists that reflect their everyday demons, which can be self deprecating humor, or other people tormenting them. There is no uniformity to the art style or content of the different submissions in this zine.
  Mental Health; psychology
- Everyday I Wish I Were A Badass Superhero, undated; Balita, Nino (Box 3, Folder 20)
  A comic about an office worker who daydreams about being a superhero in his childhood.
  Superheroes; Office Life; economics
- Examination, 2017; Cabatit, Jamie (Box 3, Folder 21)
  A zine that reflects an illicit relationship between a student and her teacher.
  Trauma; Sexuality; psychology
- Extra Rice With Extra Tries, 2015 October; Aquino, Ardie; Ardie Aquino Comics (Box 3, Folder 22)
  A mini-comic in Filipino that illustrates how depression and mental health can eat up a person. It shows how mental health impacts the way time is spent, and how many opportunities are taken or missed because of it.
  Food; Mental Health; psychology
- The Face of a Marcos Apologist, 2016 September (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Famous, 2013; Moss, Jason (Box 3, Folder 23)
  'Famous' is comprised of art drawn in traditional mediums, including pencil, marker, but mostly pen ink. The images produced stray away and strain the idea of what is desirable in art, especially in the Philippines.
  Capitalism; Desirability; Art; Culture; economics
  - Famous Volume 1, 2013 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Famous Volume 2, undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
- First Considerations, Huling Habilin, 2014; Campos, Rolf (Box 3, Folder 24)
  First Considerations, Huling Habilin (Last Will), created by Rolf Campos in 2014, serves as a template for a person's last will and testament. The pages are filled with anatomy doodles, designated areas to paste photos, final wishes for loved ones, and questions that range from asking about basic information, to deeply personal sentiments about life, death, and regrets.
  Death; Anatomy; Last Will; Art; Culture; psychology
- Flower Child, undated (Box 10, Folder 28)
- For, undated; Cadiz, Marianne (Box 3, Folder 25)
  This thin, xeroxed zine by Marianne Cadiz contains erasure poetry, which reveals a message about embracing pain as an act of sacrifice for love.
  Erasure Poetry; Romance; Martyr; Literature
- Forgive them, Lewitt, For They Know Not What They're Saying, 2012; Miranda, Donna; Suarez, Angelo V. (Box 3, Folder 26)
  This is a transcript from a talk given at the Artists' Forum on Conceptual Art Practice, Held at the Cultural Center of the Philippines on 22 March 2012.
  Transcript; Forums; Art; History; Language
- Freehand, undated; The Graphic Literature Guild; University of the Philippines at Los Baños (Box 3, Folder 27)
  A compilation of comics created by students from a recognized socio-cultural organization in the University of the Philippines Los Baños.
  Anthology; Art
  - Freehand, volume 5, issue 1 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Freehand, volume 5, issue 2 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- FUCKING ROCKSTAZZ, 2014; Enrique, Patrick; Chain Mason (Box 3, Folder 28)
  FUCKING ROCKSTAZZ is a zine by Patrick "Rawwrr" Enrique depicting popular icons such as Jesus Christ, Darth Vader, and the Philippine's national hero Jose Rizal as rockstars.
  Parody; Pop Culture; Art; Film; History; Religion; Music
- Gatas ng Saging, 2010; Estanislao, Rommel J.; Cordero, KC; Pocket-Size Indie Comics (Box 3, Folder 29)
  Gatang ng Saging is a minicomic by Rommel "Omeng" Estanislao that was published in 2010. The zine gives a brief explanation of what an "anting-anting" is, gives an example of items considered to be an anting-anting in th Philippines. The comic shows a man who went to gain powers by swallowing a talisman-milk from a banana tree.
  Anting-anting; Puso ng saging; Culture; Folklore
- A Geek's Life, undated; Collado, Daniel (Box 1, Folder 13)
  This comic by Daniel Collado illustrates his take on what characteristics Geeks have. The zine is printed in black, white and grey.
  Geek; Subculture; Culture
- Genesis, 2016; Villanueva, Julius; Azhadar Comix (Box 3, Folder 30)
  This is a comic of a fictional take on how society progressed from archeic humans, and how fire was first discovered.
  Violence; Evolution; Homo Erectus; Anthropology; Folklore; Religion; Race
- Give Ipis A Chance, 2017; Morealis, Aurora (Box 3, Folder 31)
  A comic about an Ipis, or a cockroach, that is widely shunned by society.
  Cockroaches
- Grail Comics Anthology, 2012; UP GRAIL (Box 3, Folder 32)
  A compilation of different graphic novels and comics that each tell vastly different stories. They are on a wide range of art styles, genres, and story lines that will cater to various audiences. Only two pages are in Filipino, while the rest are in English.
  Anthology; Fiction; Mermen; Folklore
- Gravy, undated; Meatfist (Box 3, Folder 33)
  A short comic about animal sailors trying to deliver gravy, but were used as bait against a sea monster.
  Ships; Sailing
- Gravy, 2016 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Gugma, undated; Baconguis, Ives; Demanawa, Sophia (Box 3, Folder 34)
  This comic is a modern take on the story between Sidapa, the deity of death, and Bulan, one of the seven moon deities, in Philippine mythology. Because these deities hail from the Bicol and Visaya region, the comic was named after the Cebuano word for "love."
  Mount Madjaas (Panay, Philippines); Bicol Peninsula (Philippines); LGBT; Sidapa; Bulan; Bakunawa; Folklore
- Guisadong Gulay, 2016-2017; Poblete, Cathy (Box 3, Folder 35)
  A zine with comics that go through the different phases after a break up. The first zine shows the liberating aspect of being single again, while the second zine reflects the regret of choosing to end the relationship in hindsight.
  Breaking Up; Heartbreak; Art; psychology
  - Masarap Magisa, 2016 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Mahirap Palang Magisa, 2017 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Guro Collection, undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
- Hands And Fingers, 2017; Tango, A. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  A short folded zine that talks about the idea that there are more people who are more interested in sex, and noncommitted relationships, than there are that do.
  Sexuality; psychology
- Hardcore Amateur Asian Teen Angst, 2016; Cabatit, Jamie (Box 4, Folder 2)
  A short comic about a 23 year old woman who falls in love with a narcissist. She reflects on her dynamic with this man, and how they went from having something really good, to having nothing between them.
  Dating; Angst; Anthropology; psychology
- Heart on your Sleeve, undated (Box 10, Folder 20)
- Help!, 2017; Diakamo; Philippine High School for the Arts (Box 4, Folder 3)
  A wordless comic about soldiers in a dug-out.
  Violence; War; Soldiers; Politics
- High Fives and Neil Young For the Road, 2013 October 09; Villacorta, Claire (Box 4, Folder 4)
  High Fives and Neil Young for the Road is an "outtakes" zine for the comic of Claire's dog following his death, but it is more of an outtakes of the process to get creativity flowing to finish the comic. In this, Claire goes through 'Writing the Unthinkable' exercises, an activity from Lynda Barry's book as part of an intensive writing workshop to word flowing from both writers and non-writers.
  Outtakes; Art; Education; Literature; Barry, Lynda
- Hola Filipinas!, 2014 May; Collado, Daniel (Box 4, Folder 5)
  A Spaniard in Manila Hola Filipinas! is a minicomic by Daniel Collado that was published in May 2014. Each page details the adventures and misadventures of Felipe, a Spaniard expat, as he gets accustomed to everyday Filipino customs and traditions in Manila.
  Manila; Tourism; Spaniard; Culture; Geography; Transportation
- Home, undated; Chernila Comics (Box 4, Folder 6)
  This comic focuses on a twin sister and the grief experienced following the death of her sister. The narrator questions the meaning of home.
  Barkada; Family; Home; psychology
- The Home Owners, 2013 November; Saturnino Basilla (Box 8, Folder 12)
  This photozine is Saturnino Basilla's 6th item, which was printed in Manila, Philippines. This photozine contains screencaps from erotic/pornographic films: 'Barbara Broadcast', 'Behind the Green Door', 'Beyond Shame', 'Devil in Miss Jones', 'Erotic Night of the Livign Dead', 'Erotikill', 'Itallian Stallion', 'Space Thing', 'Story of O', and 'Talk Dirty to me'. Despite the mature source of the images, the photozine only includes a couple of explicit images, and primarily focuses on shots that showcase the characters in their homes.
  Sexuality; Screencaps; Art; Culture; Film
- Hourly Comic Day: Birthday Edition, 2017; Custodio, Gioseppe (Box 4, Folder 7)
  Gioseppe Custodio makes a comic for every hour on the day of his birthday.
  Hourly Comic Day; Art
- Humigit-Kumulang, 2013; Liboon, Franz Joel; High Chair (Box 4, Folder 8)
  A poetry book in Filipino that surrounds the idea of being too much and not enough. There are 18 poems that are written around this theme of worth.
  Self-worth; Self-esteem; Poetry; Literature; psychology
- I am the Best, undated; Esguerra, James (Box 4, Folder 9)
  The pages in this zine are lined with caricaturized pop culture icons and characters who bear symbols like upside-down crosses, swastikas, and the KKK hood. Some drawings are offensive.
  Caricatures; Heavy Metal; Pop Culture; Dark Humor; Culture; Religion
- I Draw What People I Don't Know Talk About In The Food Court, undated; Yu, Ev (Box 4, Folder 10)
  A compilation of drawings of what Ev Yu overhears from other people in food courts. The panels contan minimal pieces of the conversations heard at food courts, but are interpreted in more abstract images instead.
  Food Court; Anthropology; Art
- If You Fall, You Fall Alone, 2010; Balisi, Allan; Blanc Compound (Box 4, Folder 11)
  This is a catalog of Allan Balisi's solo exhibition at Blanc Gallery. 'If You Fall, You Fall Alone' presents a series of monochromatic paintings with subtle hints of blue, green, brown, and other muted colors. The oil paintings mixed with graphite stand alone and are only given context by their cryptic titles.
  Graphite; Oil Painting; Exhibition Catalogs; Art
- ikaw, undated (Box 10, Folder 40)
- Ikaw Ang Una Kong Sinabihan, 2017; Mariposa XVI (Box 4, Folder 12)
  A compliation of English and Filipino poems, short stories, and illustrations from different artists about secrets and the surprising ways they are found out.
  Secrets; Poetry; Literature
- In Absentia, undated; De Guzman, Elaine (Box 4, Folder 13)
  A collection of ramblings, photos, illustrations, and poems on bipolar disorder. This zine serves as a reminder from the author to others who have bipolar disorder that they are not alone. The poems and ramblings that touch on depression and self harm are a cries for help and calls of solidarity at the same time.
  Mental Health; Suicide; Bipolar Disorder; Literature; psychology
- In The Blanks, 2013 September; Uy, Karize Michella (Box 4, Folder 14)
  This is a coloring and drawing booklet by Karize Michella Uy, which was first printed in September 2013. The illustrations in the zine are printed in a light grey, and feature small everyday items to be colored in-ranging from video game controllers, to first aid kits, to tombstones.
  Coloring Book; Art
- Increments, 2014; Cesario, Joanne; Bacabac, Michelle; 502 Komiks (Box 4, Folder 15)
  This zine contains different short comics about everyday life for its characters, including a trip to the hospital and a tour of someone's room.
  Slice of Life; Art; Literature
- Inggit, 2017 December; Mga Gago Sa Disyerto (Box 4, Folder 16)
  A zine with poems and short stories that revolve around the central theme of envy. In these short stories and poems, it is shown what kind of actions envy-driven people do, and touch on the consequences of those actions too. This is the first part to a series called the "Seven Deadly Zines," based on the seven cadinal sins.
  Jealousy; Envy; Deadly Sins; Literature; psychology
- Instead Of, 2012; Uy, Karize Michella; The Cabinet (Box 4, Folder 17)
  This is an assemblage zine, or a zine with a compilation of unrelated texts, which were extracted from the author's undergraduate thesis "The Mythological Nature of Science Fiction in the Dune Series." Despite this, 'Instead Of' still spins a love story in a futuristic setting about a lover who thinks love is greater than the fact and fiction of death itself.
  Science fiction; Literature
- intro, 2017; Mendiola, Glenn (Box 4, Folder 18)
  A photozine of black and white photography of things that are familiar in color. This zine features 20 images of things once familiar in color, but made refreshing in black and white. MONØmania, a black and white photofest in the Philippines prompted Glenn to self-publish 'intro.'
  Photography; Monochrome; Grayscale
- Iron Ladies, 2013 December; Germar, Paola; Africa, Catalina; Zoleta, Jeona; Nine Iron (Box 4, Folder 19)
  This contents of this zine, published by Saturnino Basilla in Manila, was collaborated on by nine different women. The zine Includes three trading cards that reference to different submissions inside the zine. The zine gives a bigger reference to the Thai comedy film Iron Ladies.
  Feminism; Iron Ladies; Film
- Is It Okay If I Just Look At You Lovingly For A While, undated; Rex, Austere (Box 4, Folder 20)
  This zine includes a series of single-page drawings of a gay man going on relationship ventures. He has to figure out whether to follow his brain, his heart, or his libido, as he tries to overcome his self-perceptions about his partner/s.
  LGBT; Gay Comics; Anthropology
- Isaw, 2016 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  A multimedia zine that has collages, photos, and musings. Mostly, it's a zine about cheap food and being a broke college student.
  Food; Isaw; Street Food; College Life; Culture
- Ito ang Pangalan Ng Aking Mga Dila, 2017; Hacla, Marlon; Magpies Press (Box 4, Folder 22)
  The lines for this Filipino poem is written by Estela Vadal, an artificial intelligence created by Marlon Hacla. The poignant lines in this poem go in alphabetical order, and have been picked and edited by Maron Hacla for being his AI's best lines.
  Artificial Intelligence; Recurrent Neural Network; Literature; Technology
- The Jesus Rocket / I Think My Dog is Pro-Du30 / Danger Man, 2016; de Leon, Marguerite Alcazaren (Box 8, Folder 13)